A Finding Aid to the Roko Gallery Records, 1929-1982, bulk 1970-1978, in the Archives of American Art AAA.rokogall
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition and Event Files, circa 1956-1978; Series 5; (Box 5; 0.3 linear feet)
  - Events
    - Meet the Composer Program, circa 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Poetry Readings Program, circa 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Poetry Readings Program - Biographical Materials, circa 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Poetry Readings Program - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1947-1966; Series 6; (Box 5-6; 0.5 linear feet)
  This series includes disassembled scrapbooks in their original order of printed material and clippings about solo and group exhibitions held at the Roko Gallery from 1947-1966. Among the many artists represented are Claude Clark, Beauford Delaney, Paul England, Peter Heinemann, Herbert Kallem, Herschel Levit, Si Lewen, Howard Mandel, Rose Piper, Sadie Rosenblum, Herbert Scheffel, Erika Weihs, Walter Williams, and Jan Wunderman.
  Folders are arranged chronologically according to the original order.
  - Scrapbook, circa 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 63-64)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1948-1952 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1948-1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Printed Material, 1929-1982; Series 7; (Box 6; 0.4 linear feet)
  Printed material includes newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, newsletters, pamphlets, brochures, reproductions of artwork, and miscellaneous notes. Among the exhibition catalogs, galleries represented include Buchholz Gallery, Marie Harriman Gallery, C.W. Kraushaar Art Galleries, Julian Levy Gallery, the Museum of Modern Art, Reinhardt Galleries, Valentine Gallery, and the Whitney Museum of American Art. Printed material that pre-dates the founding of the gallery was collected by Michael Freilich.
  - Clippings, 1939-1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1960-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1929-1930 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1932-1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1938-1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs, 1962-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs - Group Exhibitions, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Announcements/Catalogs - One Man Exhibitions, circa 1930s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, Primitive Art Newsletters, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, Sotheby Parke Bernet, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures, circa 1957-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures, Business Committee for the Arts, circa 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962, 1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Photographic Material, 1946-circa 1970s; Series 8; (Box 6; 0.3 linear feet)
  Found are black and white photographs, a handful of color snapshots, slides, and negatives of artwork. Photographs of gallery directors Michael Leon Freilich, Cynthia Bernadini, and Manu Sassoonian, and other unidentified people are found in this series.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material, then alphabetically by subject.
  - Photographs (Box 6)
    - Artwork by Unidentified Artists, 1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Cynthia Bernadini and Friends, circa 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Michael Leon Freilich and Friends, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Michael Leon Freilich and Friends, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Manu Sassoonian, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Negatives and Color Transparencies, Artwork, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Slides, Artwork Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Slides and Negatives, Michael Leon Freilich and Friends, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)